<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-27T16:13:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">TensorCharts Manual</title><subtitle>Documentation and tutorials about TensorCharts.com</subtitle><author><name>TensorCharts</name></author><entry><title type="html">Notification engine and TC alerts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notification_engine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notification engine and TC alerts" /><published>2018-09-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notification_engine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notification_engine/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a rough week, but we made it through. The roll-out of paid subscriptions and bug fixing took a few days, update of websocket servers, couple of sleepless nights but your support exceeded my expectations and I would like to thank you for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TensorCharts has been stable as never before for the last 4 days so I took some time to review the survey from August and ended up with a to-do list containing 100 features/items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will reshift my focus a little bit more on the front-end side in the upcoming weeks/months, improving the current features and start working on some new ones. One of which is the notification engine and alerts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of the most prevalent requests in the survey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“...make trader’s life and sleep easier with alerts and notifications. Watching market going sideways is boring and switching between markets isn’t fun either...”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;win-1-month-of-premium-plan&quot;&gt;Win 1 month of Premium plan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing a notification engine can be tricky. I will outline some ideas but your input is crucial here. Let’s design it together, this will take some time and multiple iterations to get it right but it can’t be done by one or two people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This engine should be based on order flow data, starting in the first version as a stream of events from all markets. Events like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;large trades&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;liquidations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;high trades counters ratio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;high relative trading volume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vwap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;standard deviation cross&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;price close to Volume Profile POC (VAH, VAL)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;and more…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we progress the design, these events should be accessible via  “alerts builder”, where anyone can define certain conditions and build their own notifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;example:  &lt;small&gt;(&lt;i&gt;taken from the survey, not my idea&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;IF 5min_counters_ratio &amp;lt; -2 
AND 5min_rel_volume &amp;gt; 3 
AND 2min_large_trades &amp;gt; 400 
= sendAlert(email)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three best answers of the following survey will &lt;strong&gt;win 1 month of PREMIUM plan&lt;/strong&gt; (ends 30.9.2018)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/7UBVmTJhf84PXzQj1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/forms/7UBVmTJhf84PXzQj1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to reading your ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a good one,
&lt;br /&gt;
David.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David</name></author><category term="notifications" /><summary type="html">It’s been a rough week, but we made it through. The roll-out of paid subscriptions and bug fixing took a few days, update of websocket servers, couple of sleepless nights but your support exceeded my expectations and I would like to thank you for that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paid plans coming to TensorCharts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/paid-plans-v01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paid plans coming to TensorCharts" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/paid-plans-v01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/paid-plans-v01/">&lt;p&gt;It’ll be almost  a year since the first prototype of TensorCharts (&lt;strong&gt;TC&lt;/strong&gt;) was released. Now it’s time to move TC to another phase and with your help, create the best trading platform for crypto and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monetization has always been a pain point for me. I love building products, but thinking about pricing, paid plans, upselling and what not is killing me. But it needs to be done. Great products don’t come for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing-data&quot;&gt;PRICING DATA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few days ago, we ran a survey out of  which we gathered hundreds of responses on customer satisfaction and value based price sensitivity (Van Westendorp methodology). I will reveal the complete results of the survey in the upcoming weeks, but let’s focus on price related questions for now, we asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Too expensive)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;At what price would you think TC to be so expensive that you would not consider buying it?&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
(Too cheap) 	
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;At what price would you think TC to be so cheap that you would question the quality?&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
(Expensive/High Side) 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;At what price would you think TC is starting to get expensive, but you would still consider it?&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
(Good Value)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;At what price would you think TC to be a bargain—a great buy for the money?&lt;/em&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the great TC community, we were able to collect statistically significant data. Some answers were filtered/removed if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“high side” was greater than “too expensive”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“too expensive” was less than 3 dollars (outliers, don’t see value in TC)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“too expensive” was greater than 150 dollars (outliers, top 99 percentile)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“good value” less or equal to 0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;incomplete answers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;delete “too cheap” column (not useful for a webapp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t dive into the specifics of Van Westendorp methodology, but the result was quite clear. Intersections of each category define optimal price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure data-uk-lightbox=&quot;animation: slide&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;uk-inline&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/posts/tcPriceSensitivity.png&quot; caption=&quot;Van Westendorp price analysis&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/posts/tcPriceSensitivity.png&quot; alt=&quot;TensorCharts Price sensitivity&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;uk-position-center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span data-uk-overlay-icon=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption data-uk-grid=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;uk-flex-right&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;uk-width-auto&quot;&gt;Van Westendorp price analysis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TensorCharts optimal price lies in between $20 and $30 per month. About 35% of users would find $20 a “good value” and it would still be an acceptable price for 65%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-price-fits-all&quot;&gt;NO PRICE FITS ALL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last 8 months, I’ve spent hours talking to you, users of TensorCharts and realized crypto traders are a very diverse group of people. Some very wealthy, long-term profitable, on the other hand most of you struggling or losing great amount of money. I do believe TC can help people see unseen and change the way they look at trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to justify $20 per month for those losing though, even if it helps them get out of their losing streak. That’s why we tried to come up with a business model which wouldn’t disqualify newcomers or losing traders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played quite a bit with the idea of fully customizable TC, where you would pay very low starting fee and only pay few cents for each feature you selected. This way, you could test all features without paying a high priced full featured plan. But it felt too complicated, with too many options leading to decision paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paid-plans-v01&quot;&gt;PAID PLANS v0.1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up with a completely different and also not very common pricing model. I’ve always loved Spotify pricing with its free, premium and family plan and that’s where we got the inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TensorCharts will offer a &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt; plan, with no advanced features, but you’ll get the order flow experience. Newcomers will be able to see trades and orderbook heatmaps. If they decide to move their game to another level, they can choose from two paid plans, &lt;strong&gt;PREMIUM ($18)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;TEAM ($8 per user)&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll get all advanced features and fast/good data update rate in both plans. In TEAM, you can &lt;em&gt;save more than 55%&lt;/em&gt; if you find 4 more traders for your team, compared to PREMIUM model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look again at the price sensitivity chart, 83% of users think &lt;strong&gt;$8&lt;/strong&gt; is a “good value”.  Also according to our survey, 68% of users believe TC is better than competitors (25% thinks we are equal) but $8 is way under any other competitor out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we are fools, but it feels just right at this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-overview&quot;&gt;QUICK OVERVIEW&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure data-uk-lightbox=&quot;animation: slide&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;uk-inline&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/posts/paid_plans_overview.png&quot; caption=&quot;Paid plans quick overview&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/posts/paid_plans_overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paid plans quick overview&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;uk-position-center&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span data-uk-overlay-icon=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption data-uk-grid=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;uk-flex-right&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;uk-width-auto&quot;&gt;Paid plans quick overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;full overview&lt;/strong&gt;, you can check out this link:
&lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1lLV9o4i3JzcW1oB5qLayphra22SPWGyLtyfO5Ef9p8I/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1lLV9o4i3JzcW1oB5qLayphra22SPWGyLtyfO5Ef9p8I/edit?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;FINAL NOTES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve tried really hard to come up with an affordable yet still financially sustainable business model which won’t limit newcomers or losing traders. I would love to hear your thoughts, pricing is an ongoing process and we welcome any suggestions, input or ideas. 
You can contact me at  &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:david@tensorcharts.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;david@tensorcharts.com&lt;/a&gt; or via 
&lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://discord.gg/3uE5Rr7&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payment processing and paid plans will be implemented in the next 2-3 weeks, supporting crypto payments only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a good one,
&lt;br /&gt;
David.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David</name></author><category term="pricing" /><summary type="html">It’ll be almost a year since the first prototype of TensorCharts (TC) was released. Now it’s time to move TC to another phase and with your help, create the best trading platform for crypto and beyond.</summary></entry></feed>